PERFECT CROWN
SPONSORED BY: MINISTRY OF
CULTURE, SPORTS AND TOURISM
AND KOREA CREATIVE
CONTENT AGENCY
MBC DRAMA SCRIPT
CONTEST WINNER
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS
WERE FILMED SAFELY
PROMISING THE END, NOT FOREVER…
EXCLUSIVE: THE ROYAL COUPLE'S
MARRIAGE CONTRACT LEAKED
Is it true that
the marriage is contractual?
Is it true you plan to
divorce in three years? Please respond!
ROYAL ACADEMY
80TH ANNIVERSARY CELEBRATION
Did you intentionally
deceive the people?
This is a betrayal of the public!
What has Castle Group
promised the Crown?
- Is it true?
- Are the allegations true?
What are you doing?
Keep your eyes on me.
PERFECT CROWN
EPISODE 9
Let's get you out first.
Your Royal Highness.
It's swarming with reporters
and students outside.
What should we do?
- And the Royal Guard?
- We had dispatched the bare minimum.
I'll leave first.
- You two can...
- Your Royal Highness!
I don't want to.
Let's leave together.
There they are!
Any words
for the people watching?
Is it all true?
Are the allegations true?
What comes after divorce?
- Are you confirming the allegations?
- Your Royal Highness!
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Your Royal Highness, what say you?
- Are the allegations true?
- Your Royal Highness!
- Please give us a response!
Are the allegations true?
Is it true that
this is a marriage of convenience?
- Oh, no…
- They're tinted windows, Hyejeong.
Really? Thank goodness.
Right.
Why isn't this working?
They should be okay, right?
I think so.
They have Prime Minister Min, so…
Right. I should update
the Royal Guard.
Right. I should also update
the Royal Secretariat.
Is there any truth
to the allegations?
Any response to the allegations?
We must hurry!
Your Majesty.
Where are the Grand Prince and Princess?
You see, they are…
Reporters are camped out
in front of the palace.
This should be the safest option.
Sir.
The party is asking
about the crisis meeting.
Tell them they'll have to wait.
Make sure no one talks to the press
to avoid speculative coverage.
Yes, sir.
Foreign Affairs is asking
about the overseas tour…
- Submit it in writing.
- Yes, sir.
Amid growing fallout
from the leaked marriage contract,
the controversy is escalating
beyond a mere private-life scandal,
even drawing scrutiny
over the monarchy's credibility.
The alleged preferential treatment
the Grand Princess received,
and the suspension
of the Junghwajeon fire investigation…
…have emerged
as the central points of this controversy.
Huiju.
Seong Huiju.
- Seong Huiju.
- In response, the Crown
has stated it is verifying the facts,
maintaining a cautious stance.
However, critics argue
that the possibility of the exercise
of private influence cannot be ruled out.
Both the Crown and the Cabinet
are reportedly conducting…
Are you okay?
However, neither has yet
released an official statement.
Yes.
Let's start by confirming a few things.
First of all,
did you two draw up
the marriage contract yourselves?
Besides me, does anyone else know
that this marriage is fake?
Aside from my personal aide,
there's no one else.
Just Ms. Do.
I haven't discussed it
with the Royal Secretariat yet,
but they will most likely
choose not to respond.
What do you mean?
As long as the contract is real,
any explanation or defense
will only stir up more noise.
So, are you asking us to stay silent?
Yes. Precisely, Your Royal Highness.
Waiting for things
to die down could backfire on us.
We must wait until even that dies down.
It was only…
a farce in the beginning.
"It only started out as deception."
Is that what you'll say?
The contract stipulates
a divorce within three years.
Can you guarantee
there will be no divorce?
Can you?
Sir.
You really should see this.
Excuse me for a moment.
I wondered why that brat
would just hand over the company.
Turns out she had a whole plan.
What about that kiss over the palace wall?
Was that fake too?
Of course, it was!
Then what about when she collapsed,
and he carried her out in his arms?
Was that all just an act?
Babe, who cares about that right now?
Our family is about to be ruined!
Well, I'm just worried about Huiju…
What is it now?
What's with all the messages?
ANOTHER SCANDAL WILL BREAK THIS WEEK…
I wondered why Prince I-AN
would marry a love child…
He clearly married
for Castle Group.
So all that talk
about Prince Suyang…
Was her fainting
at the wedding just a stunt?
Babe.
What the hell is going on?
As public trust in the royal couple wavers
following the leak
of their marriage contract earlier today,
incendiary allegations have surfaced
that Grand Princess Seong received
preferential treatment
even prior to the royal wedding.
Grand Princess Seong had previously
been identified as the prime suspect
in the Junghwajeon Hall fire
that broke out
during His Majesty's
Royal Birthday Banquet.
Some critics argue that the Grand Prince
may have intervened in the investigation
for personal reasons.
Some are even voicing concerns
whether he is connected
to the Junghwajeon Hall fire incident.
The political sphere is adopting
a cautious stance,
while the palace and the Cabinet…
Are you scared?
You have to have honor
for disgrace to mean anything.
I've never had any, so I'm fine.
Are you okay?
Honor is all you have.
Are you scared?
Yes.
I am afraid…
that my honor will end up…
harming you.
I believe it's best
for you both to return to the palace now.
What about all the reporters there?
Are you sure it's okay?
They're planning a protest
outside the palace tomorrow morning.
A protest?
What are you talking about?
There's a rumor that
you're vying for the throne.
The Junghwajeon fire is being interpreted
to fit that narrative.
That's absolute nonsense.
Securing your safety comes first.
Return to the palace.
It appears the protest cannot be stopped.
Nothing could possibly stop it now.
To be loved is to be hated
in equal measure.
Nothing stokes gossip like the downfall
of the high and mighty.
Did you deliver the message to Father?
He sent word that he is on his way.
Prepare to enter the Council Hall.
Your Royal Highness.
You should make your way
to the Council Hall.
Now?
Her Majesty has summoned
the Office of Royal Relatives.
Announcing Grand Prince I-AN.
Your Majesty.
Have you summoned the royal relatives?
- Let's discuss it privately.
- I do not wish to hear your excuses.
- Queen Mother.
- How dare you!
To deceive the people
and bring disgrace upon the Crown.
Do you truly believe you can be forgiven?
You, who sold off your royal status.
And you, who purchased it.
You would do well to prepare yourselves.
I found it rather peculiar from the start,
how she seemed to have no regard
for royal tradition or decorum.
You should stop there.
"It is simply
because of her low pedigree."
That was my oversight.
You thought you could protect yourself
with that measly contract?
I cannot tell if you are naïve or foolish.
Senior Sixth Rank, Choi Hyeon.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Junior Sixth Rank, Do Hyejeong.
Your superiors are unworthy
of an audience in the Council Hall.
Escort them out.
Your Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness!
I'm fine, so just…
You're far from fine!
Who clenches their fist this hard
out of anger?
Just look at this hand.
Stay put.
I'll have Aide Choi get some…
I'm fine.
It doesn't hurt.
This is insane.
It's hit the lower limit.
What if the chairman calls me
to his office? That won't end well.
Hello.
Seriously?
Aide Do!
Yes?
We have a problem.
Why? What is it now?
There's an article claiming
the Grand Princess faked her collapse.
What?
What are you talking about?
THE REASON WHY SHE FAINTED…
WAS THE COLLAPSE STAGED?
It sounds like…
This is about to blow up in our face.
WAS THE COLLAPSE STAGED?
PRESSURE MOUNTS ON ROYAL FAMILY
Remove Grand Prince I-AN
as regent!
Remove him! Remove him!
Grand Prince I-AN
and Seong Huiju must apologize!
Apologize! Apologize!
Remove Grand Prince I-AN
as regent!
Remove him! Remove him!
Strip Seong Huiju
of her rank immediately!
Immediately! Immediately!
We cannot wait any longer.
Your Royal Highness.
They're going so far as to suggest
that my wife fainted for show.
I shall set the record straight myself.
Our marriage may have started
with a contract,
but everything we've shown the people
is genuine.
Your Royal Highness.
Even if the substance found in her system
was one prescribed to me,
there is nothing I seek to gain
at the cost of her life.
What about the claim
that you're vying for the crown?
Will you deny that as well?
- Prime Minister Min.
- Answer me, sir.
Will you deny it?
If I do not deny it,
how would you respond?
"We do not need a king
who lacks the people's support."
That's how I would respond.
Thus, Your Royal Highness…
For the sake of the Crown and the nation,
I humbly request…
that you end your regency.
5 DAYS BEFORE THE CONTRACT LEAK
Sir.
They discovered traces of digoxin
in a goblet used in the wedding rites.
PHOTO 1: GOBLET CONTAINING
TRACES OF DIGOXIN
Sir, Ms. Lee Areum has arrived.
I heard you asked to see me.
PERSONAL DETAILS: LEE AREUM
IN CHARGE OF THE NUPTIAL WINE
PARK MALJA, HER MOTHER,
BECAME AN ALCOHOLIC…
IN NEED OF FUNDS
FOR BROTHER'S KIDNEY TRANSPLANT
I was instructed to simply grind it up
and rub it on the Grand Prince's goblet.
I had no idea what it was.
I was told if I didn't do it,
my brother's surgery might be delayed…
Do you think it's true?
We'll have to verify it.
But I still don't understand why.
Did they really need to kill him?
I get that he was bothersome…
4 DAYS BEFORE THE CONTRACT LEAK
Prime Minister Min.
What could you possibly
be suggesting right now?
Here's evidence
proving it was a poisoning.
A staff testified that the Grand Prince
was the intended target.
She confirmed the substance used
and her cryptocurrency records.
She also testified
that the compensation
came from Lord INPYEONG.
This is slander.
How dare you suspect my father
on a mere servant's word?
- You are also under suspicion.
- Prime Minister Min!
Can you prove you had no knowledge
of Lord INPYEONG's actions?
Your Majesty,
Grand Prince I-AN has arrived.
His Royal Highness remains unaware.
Allow me some time.
Your Majesty.
Prime Minister Min.
Until tonight.
That is all I can provide you.
I shall send word.
What brings you here, Prime Minister Min?
I came to request her cooperation
in the investigation.
The Inner Court will be summoned tomorrow.
I'm here to discuss
the Anhwadang Hall staff.
Your Majesty?
I heard you were looking
to replace the attendants.
Are you feeling unwell?
The Grand Princess collapsed
at the wedding.
Now, the Grand Prince seeks
to replace innocent attendants.
The palace is in disarray, is it not?
Jeongwoo!
Should you be outside already?
Did the doctor…
I don't need to hear that
from you too.
My ears are about to bleed as it is.
It appears she is weary from all the care
the Grand Prince has taken
to protect the Grand Princess.
Given how devoted they are to each other,
producing an heir should not be…
What…
…in the world are you talking about?
In broad daylight, no less.
Are you free for a short walk?
How's the investigation going?
Are you getting anywhere?
Can we trust Royal Seoul Hospital?
If you want, I can have Castle Hospital…
What?
It seems real.
What does?
Your devotion?
Devotion? As if.
Can't I even show
this much concern for my spouse?
My goodness.
You know our marriage is only for show.
How are we supposed to fool the nation
if we can't even fool the staff?
So?
You're trying to fool me too?
What?
Sir.
His Majesty is due to give
his witness statement shortly.
I should go.
But I'm not done talking yet…
I'll call you later…
Evidence that proves
it was a poisoning.
A staff testified that the Grand Prince
was the intended target.
She confirmed the drug used
and her cryptocurrency records.
She testified the compensation
came from Lord INPYEONG.
Your Majesty.
What brings you here unannounced?
Explain yourself.
- Your Majesty.
- I said!
Explain yourself.
Tell me it was not you.
PERSONAL DETAILS: LEE AREUM
WITNESS STATEMENT
Where did you get this?
I asked where you got this.
Were you truly attempting to murder
the Grand Prince?
Have you lost your mind?
If this gets out,
you, me, and His Majesty will be...
That is…
exactly why the Grand Prince
must be eliminated.
Why do you think the Grand Prince,
who feigned ignorance,
has chosen to speak up now?
Not only did you burn
the late King's final royal edict.
But imagine
what would happen if he discovers
the same fire killed the late King.
I had nothing to do
with the late King's death!
Who would ever believe
such a feeble excuse?
Father…
"I only intended to burn the royal edict.
I never intended for that fire
to burn down the palace hall
and take the King's life."
Is that what you will say?
Is that what you have thought of me
all this time?
What Your Majesty has done
is not my concern.
You must do whatever it takes
to keep His Majesty safe.
That is the only way
to ensure your own safety,
mine, and our family name.
Now, tell me.
Where did you
get this from?
Your Majesty.
Grand Princess.
You would do well to tread carefully.
Sir.
The Queen Mother is calling. It's urgent.
I'll connect you now.
HUIJU
3 DAYS BEFORE THE CONTRACT LEAK
How does it feel
to have the man hailed
as the greatest prime minister in history
as a father?
PRIME MINISTER MIN SEUNGJAE
I'm not sure.
How does it feel
to have a father who will be known
as the most dangerous lord
in history?
That will not be his legacy.
Are you denying it?
I wish to make a request.
I thought about what would lead you
to bring me that evidence.
If I were a suspect in your eyes…
why did you come to me
and not the Grand Prince?
Do you wish to have the Grand Princess?
MARRIAGE CONTRACT
Should that come to light,
the court will be in turmoil
and the nation in chaos.
All the benefits outlined in the contract
favor the Grand Princess.
Thus, the tide of condemnation
will break upon her.
Do you think I would just let that happen?
It is clear you are intent
on taking her for yourself.
And you do not want her to suffer, either?
Then,
I shall redirect that tide to Prince I-AN.
The more the Grand Prince
is driven to the brink,
the more her resolve
is bound to crumble, is it not?
What is the matter?
Did you presume I could not perceive
what you so plainly see between them?
The Grand Prince smiles
when he drives too.
He can be so childlike sometimes.
He's in danger right now!
I like Seong Huiju.
You have tonight to consider your options.
That is all I can provide you.
Do you possess the authority to request…
that I end the regency?
I have a duty to protect the Crown.
You make it sound…
as though I sought to harm it.
The Crown represents the nation.
As long as you represent the Crown,
you and the Crown
are one.
So?
Face your downfall alone.
I will not allow you
to drag the Crown down with you.
A private meeting with Prime Minister Min?
Yes, Your Majesty.
They started early this morning.
It has already been three hours.
The Cabinet must be feeling
the pressure as well.
What about Seong Huiju?
Pardon?
Is the Grand Princess alone right now?
What?
He told him to end his regency?
Jeongwoo did?
Yes.
I mean, I really trusted
Prime Minister Min.
I know we're in a tight spot and all,
but it's not like he doesn't know
what's going on.
They crossed a line here, didn't they?
The Queen Mother is asking for you.
Well, I'm about to lose it.
How does it feel?
How does it feel to have dragged down
the cherished prince of the nation?
He had his moments of eccentricity
and would sometimes go astray,
but until he met you, I-AN was…
the pride of the Crown.
What did you offer him?
What did he gain
by elevating you so?
Did you not read the contract?
His Royal Highness
does not want anything from me.
He even settled for three years,
as long as I was with him.
So I simply agreed to do so.
How does it feel
to have dragged down
the cherished prince of the nation?
Your Royal Highness.
You should head to the King's Quarters.
Has His Majesty summoned me?
I believe Lord INPYEONG is there
with a formal appeal to the king
and even a public petition.
Emergency.
Come to the King's Quarters
when you see this.
THE NOBLE COUNCIL LEADER
AND 190 MEMBERS…
THE LOVE STORY
THAT FOOLED THE NATION…
Your Majesty.
The Crown will crumble at this rate.
Even the Grand Prince
cannot defy your royal command.
But Uncle…
Your Majesty!
Have you not heard the rumors
spreading among the people?
- The fire that took the late king…
- That is not true!
Father was not…
The Grand Prince knows that you are weak,
that is why...
Your Majesty.
The Grand Prince…
How dare you show
such insolence before His Majesty!
How dare you!
How dare you threaten His Majesty?
Why you…
Uncle…
Enter, Court Lady Jung.
Your Royal Highness!
Escort His Majesty out.
Do you not hear me?
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Grand Prince…
Your Majesty.
Do you think I'm oblivious
to your scheming?
Your… Royal…
Your Royal Highness!
Your Royal Highness.
Please let him go first…
Are you afraid I will become king?
If you wish to drive me from the palace,
you will
have to kill me first.
Your Royal Highness!
If you threaten my nephew again…
you shall not be granted a merciful death.
Uncle…
THAT DAY, 3 YEARS AGO
The Queen is inside.
Please wait here for a moment.
Understood.
Uncle!
You intend for Grand Prince I-AN
to ascend the throne?
Have you truly gone mad?
It will be better than dying.
It would be better to die.
I would rather see you dead.
For the sake of the Crown Prince.
My Queen!
Your Majesty.
Yes…
Yes?
If you are ever scared…
…you must come to me.
Whenever that may be.
Come to me…
whenever you get scared.
Yes, Uncle.
What's wrong?
What?
Did you wrong me somehow?
Earlier…
Sorry.
For what?
That unpleasant sight.
I thought it was pleasant.
What?
You did well.
You must fight back
if you wish…
to protect something.
Any likes or dislikes?
All of a sudden?
Well, I like…
Flowers. I do like them the most.
What?
- Not you.
- Pardon?
What does the Grand Prince like?
Oh. I see.
The Grand Prince.
- So silly.
- Unbelievable.
Why do you ask?
More stress is
the only thing waiting for him.
I thought I could do
something nice for him.
Maybe a favorite snack or music?
Let me think.
Black tea? He likes black tea.
He also likes bitter chocolate.
What about music?
Nope. He doesn't like anything loud.
What about his favorite scent?
Scent?
Like incense sticks or diffusers.
That will get you kicked out instantly.
He flipped out the last time
I put on some cologne.
Noted. I should stop.
Did you show
the Grand Princess the same care?
Yes.
One works best without distractions.
What about you, Hyejeong?
Pardon?
I mean, it looks like you just know
the names of flowers.
You don't seem that crazy about tea.
What do you like, Hyejeong?
Well…
I…
I was
just curious. That's all.
Such nice weather.
I'm scared
that my honor will end up…
harming you.
Me too.
I'm scared I might end up…
ruining you.
Seong Huiju!
I know public opinion's in the gutter,
but a prosecutor's investigation?
Seriously?
I'm dying over here with tanking stocks.
What the hell are you talking about?
All the board members
have been subpoenaed.
Father is about to be summoned
at this rate.
Okay, I'll be there this afternoon.
What's wrong?
Is something happening at the company?
No. I guess Father is a bit unwell.
The chairman?
- Then we should visit him...
- No need for all that.
That will only end up attracting a crowd.
It'll be better if I make
a quick run with Aide Choi.
- It's nothing serious anyway.
- But still…
You two need to attend court.
Go on.
Let's have another productive day today.
I'll call you.
Good luck!
Get a car ready.
You want to go now?
Not an escort vehicle.
One that I can drive.
Understood.
What do I have to do?
You must know.
Both the company and the palace
are a complete train wreck.
And there's nothing I can do.
At this rate…
So tell me.
Tell me what I should do.
For now,
do nothing.
- What?
- I'll make sure you don't get hurt, so...
I'm not asking you to protect me.
You're not even pretending now?
What?
You said it was all for show.
You and the Grand Prince.
I don't think that's true now.
What's that supposed to mean?
I like him.
The Grand Prince.
A lot.
That is…
quite unfortunate.
To the chairman now?
Let's go now.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
I messed up.
What are you doing?
Huiju.
I deceived you…
and hurt the company.
I'm sorry for all of it.
Please help me.
Just this once, please help me, Father.
I want to make things right…
but I don't know how.
And you call yourself a businesswoman…
Tell me.
Who are you trying to save here? Yourself?
Or the Grand Prince?
Um, I heard you enjoyed black tea.
Thank you.
Perhaps you might consider
taking a few days off?
What's going on?
The Prime Minister's Office has requested
that you cease your official duties.
A request?
Maybe just for a few days…
NEW MESSAGE
I'll be there soon.
Do not say anything to my wife.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness.
How's your father doing?
What's this? A gift?
Your Royal Highness.
Yes?
Let's get a divorce.
EPILOGUE
Tell me.
Who are you trying to save here? Yourself?
Or the Grand Prince?
Him.
I can save myself.
You…
Please, Father.
PERFECT CROWN
I want to cut my losses.
Let's get a divorce.
Is this how it felt?
Are they really
going to get divorced?
You must stop either
the Grand Prince or His Majesty.
Do whatever you must.
But you lost it all.
What could you possibly do for me now?
Did you truly believe
I could not protect us?
Surely you do not intend to accept.
I need the girl I hid
brought to the palace.
You did not trust me.
The palace gates
will be shut soon.
Let's see this through.
I will be by your side.
Translated by Justin S. Kim
PERFECT CROWN